// Additional strings for which translations could be got from Medieval translations
IDS_CT_ARMY_PANIC, "testing for army panic", // usage: Our hoplites (5) testing for army panic
IDS_CT_PROXIMITY_GENERAL, "seeing general fall nearby", // usage: Our hoplites (5) seeing general fall nearby
IDS_CT_PROXIMITY_UNIT, "seeing friends rout nearby", // usage: Our hoplites (5) seeing friends rout nearby
IDS_CT_TYPE10, "Proximity",
IDS_CT_TYPE11, "Army Panic Test",
IDS_CT_TYPE5, "Automatic Drop",
IDS_CT_TYPE6, "Proximity",
IDS_CT_TYPE7, "General Fallen",
IDS_CT_TYPE8, "Charged while Fragmented",
IDS_CT_TYPE9, "Falling Back",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_30, "Hold Fast!",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_31, "Attack!",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_58, "Bring up the reinforcements from the rear.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_59, "Attempt a flank march with your reinforcements.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_60, "Engage them in fair and open battle.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_61, "Send some units on a wide flank march to surprise the enemy by arriving behind their flank.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_62, "Send the majority of your forces to make a surprise attack on the enemy flank.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_63, "Offer battle.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_64, "Offer battle.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_INTRO_19, "The enemy have a major advantage in forces. However, their supplies are running low, and if you can hold till nightfall they will be forced to retreat.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_INTRO_20, "The enemy have manoeuvred their army to get between us and our supply line. We must defeat them by nightfall, or we will be forced to retreat.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_INTRO_35, "You have encountered the enemy army but some of your forces have not yet arrived. Should you bring them up from the rear as they arrive, or attempt to turn the situation to your advantage by marching the faster units round to take the enemy in the flank?",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_INTRO_36, "The enemy appear willing to accept battle:",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_INTRO_37, "The enemy are approaching with superior forces. You have the choice of offering open battle at a disadvantage, or setting up an ambush.",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_INTRO_38, "The enemy appear willing to accept battle:",
IDS_MPS_CHOICE_INTRO_39, "The enemy have a moderate advantage in forces and appear eager to give battle. Their overconfidence may be their undoing:",
IDS_MPS_DISBANDED3, "Your old army has been disbanded.",
IDS_SKIRMISH_EXPECTED7, "They are expected to arrive next turn.",
IDS_SKIRMISH_EXPECTED8, "They are expected to arrive this turn.",
IDS_SKIRMISH_FLANK_MARCH_INTRO3, "Our flank marchers have arrived.",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_12,"Ambush (Own)",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_13,"Ambush (Enemy)",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_14,"Open Battle (Enemy Overconfident)",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_8, "Own Side Defending",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_9, "Enemy Defending",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_INFO_12, "You have ambushed the enemy.",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_INFO_13, "The enemy have ambushed you.",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_INFO_14,"The enemy are offering open battle. Their forces outmatch yours, which may lead them to be overconfident.",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_INFO_8, "You have manoeuvred the enemy into a situation where they must attack you. If you can hold out till nightfall you will achieve a strategic victory.",
IDS_SKIRMISH_TYPE_INFO_9, "The enemy have manoeuvred you into a position where you must attack them. If they can hold out till nightfall they will achieve a strategic victory.",
