// Campaign layer strings

IDS_AND, "and",
IDS_CAMP_ABANDON_SIEGE, "has abandoned the siege of", // usage: The French 1st army has abandoned the siege of Volderheim
IDS_CAMP_ADVANTAGE, "advantage", // usage: Major French advantage
IDS_CAMP_ARMY, "Army",
IDS_CAMP_ARMYLIST0, "Own Army List",
IDS_CAMP_ARMYLIST1, "Enemy Army List",
IDS_CAMP_AVOID, "to avoid battle", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army retreated to Weisskloster from Quakenwald to avoid battle
IDS_CAMP_BALANCE, "Balance of Power",
IDS_CAMP_BATTLE, "Battle has been joined in the", // usage: Battle has been joined in the Agricultural province of Klagenfeld
IDS_CAMP_BATTLE2, "Battle has been joined near", // usage: Battle has been joined near Klagenfeld
IDS_CAMP_BESIEGED, "besieged", // usage: Catholic forces besieged Klosterheim
IDS_CAMP_CITY_FALL, "Chance of city falling this turn",
IDS_CAMP_COMBINED, "have been incorporated into the", // usage: Polish forces near Berlin have been incorporated into the Polish 1st army
IDS_CAMP_COMBINE_ARMIES, "Combine Armies",
IDS_CAMP_CURRENT_TAX_VALUE, "Current Tax Value",
IDS_CAMP_DECLINED_BATTLE,"declined battle and fell back to", // usage: The Danish 2nd army declined battle and fell back to Holstein
IDS_CAMP_DEFEAT, "You have been defeated",
IDS_CAMP_DEFEAT2, "Perhaps, once the treaty expires, you will be able to renew hostilities with more success",
IDS_CAMP_DEFEATS, "Defeats",
IDS_CAMP_DEFENCE_VALUE, "Defense Value",
IDS_CAMP_DEFENSIVE, "took up a strong defensive position", // usage: The Austrian 3rd army took up a strong defensive position.
IDS_CAMP_DETACH, "was too large to be manageable. The excess units have been detached to form the", // usage: The French 1st army was too large to be manageable. The excess units have been detached to form the French 5th army.
IDS_CAMP_END_TURN, "End Turn",
IDS_CAMP_END_TURN_CONFIRM, "Are you sure you want to end the turn?",
IDS_CAMP_ESTIMATED_TAX_VALUE, "Estimated Tax Value",
IDS_CAMP_EXIT, "Exit Campaign",
IDS_CAMP_EXIT_CONFIRM, "Are you sure you want to exit the campaign? (All unsaved data will be lost)",
IDS_CAMP_FALLEN, "has fallen to the", // usage: Dornfeld has fallen to the Spanish
IDS_CAMP_FORCES, "forces",
IDS_CAMP_GARRISON, "Garrison installed",
IDS_CAMP_INADEQUATE_SUPPLY, "were inadequately supplied", // usage: Catholic forces near Wedelburg were inadequately supplied.
IDS_CAMP_INSTRUCTIONS_START_BATTLE, "Close this window and use the Start Battle button at the bottom right of the screen to start the battle.",
IDS_CAMP_INTRO_SELECTION, "Select your side and then the two army lists~that will be used for the opposing armies~throughout the campaign.",
IDS_CAMP_JOINED, "have joined their army", // usage: Local Transylvanian forces near Jeverhausen have joined their army
IDS_CAMP_LOAD_SAVE, "Load/Save",
IDS_CAMP_LOCAL, "Local", // usage: Local Transylvanian forces near Jeverhausen have joined their army
IDS_CAMP_LOST, "They lost", // usage: They lost 535 men
IDS_CAMP_LOST2, "lost", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army lost 535 men
IDS_CAMP_LOST_BATTLE, "lost the battle", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army lost the battle near Dornfeld
IDS_CAMP_MAJOR, "Major", // usage: Major French advantage
IDS_CAMP_MANPOWER, "Available Manpower (points)",
IDS_CAMP_MEN, "men", // usage: They lost 535 men
IDS_CAMP_MOBILISED, "has been mobilized near", // usage: The Weimarian 3rd army has been mobilised near Klosterheim
IDS_CAMP_MOVED, "moved from", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army moved from Quakenwald to Weisskloster
IDS_CAMP_PROVINCE, "Region",
IDS_CAMP_PROVINCES_GAINED, "Provinces gained",
IDS_CAMP_PROVINCES_LOST, "Provinces lost",
IDS_CAMP_PROVINCE_OF, "The province of", // usage: The province of the Jeverhausen has fallen to the French forces
IDS_CAMP_RAISE_ARMY, "Raise New Army",
IDS_CAMP_REFIT_ARMY, "Refit Army",
IDS_CAMP_RETREAT, "retreated", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army retreated to Sigishoara"
IDS_CAMP_SAVE_AND_EXIT, "Save campaign and exit to main menu",
IDS_CAMP_SCENARIO_DEFENSIVE, "are dug into defensive positions",
IDS_CAMP_SCENARIO_OPEN, "are offering open battle",
IDS_CAMP_SCENARIO_REINFORCEMENTS, "have not yet all arrived",
IDS_CAMP_SCORE, "Overall prestige",
IDS_CAMP_SETUP_OK, "Proceed with campaign",
IDS_CAMP_SIEGE, "UNDER SIEGE",
IDS_CAMP_SLIGHT, "Slight", // usahe: Slight French advantage
IDS_CAMP_SPLITTING, "Splitting", // usage: Splitting Transylvanian 3rd army:
IDS_CAMP_SPLIT_ARMY, "Split Army",
IDS_CAMP_START_BATTLE, "Start Battle",
IDS_CAMP_SUED_FOR_PEACE, "leaders have sued for peace", // usage: Our leaders have sued for peace.
IDS_CAMP_SUPPLY, "Supply Limit (points)",
IDS_CAMP_SUPPLY_SHORTAGE, "SUPPLY SHORTAGE",
IDS_CAMP_SUPPLY_SHORTAGE_SEVERE, "SEVERE SUPPLY SHORTAGE",
IDS_CAMP_TERRAIN_0, "agricultural province of",
IDS_CAMP_TERRAIN_1, "hilly province of",
IDS_CAMP_TERRAIN_2, "wooded province of",
IDS_CAMP_TERRAIN_3, "mountainous province of",
IDS_CAMP_TREASURY, "Treasury",
IDS_CAMP_TURN0, "Early Spring",
IDS_CAMP_TURN1, "Late Spring",
IDS_CAMP_TURN2, "Early Summer",
IDS_CAMP_TURN3, "Late Summer",
IDS_CAMP_TURN4, "Early Autumn",
IDS_CAMP_TURN5, "Late Autumn",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL10, "When the size of the forces in a province at the end of a turn exceed the available supply limit, the armies will suffer attrition (loss of men and elan). The amount of attrition will depend on the severity of the supply shortage, which depends on the amount by which the forces present exceed the supply limit.~~Similarly a province where the size of forces (of both sides) present exceeds the province's supply limit will suffer economic damage. This affects its future capacity to pay tax and supply armies. Hostile forces in a province will cause further economic damage due to foraging raids and deliberate devastation.~~Economic damage will recover somewhat between campaigning seasons, so the province will eventually recover its original economic and supply value if given sufficent respite from conflict.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL11, "After a battle, the units of the winning side gain experience and elan. Those of the losing side gain experience but lose elan. Routing or dispersed units suffer even greater loss of elan. (Unit quality as reported during battles is calculated from the average of the unit's experience and elan).~~Units that suffered no casualties at all during the battle are assumed not to have fought and hence do not gain experience. Units that have suffered particularly heavy losses may be disbanded and their men drafted into other units to replace losses.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL12, "At the end of each year taxes are collected and troops paid. Captured provinces only yield half of their normal taxeable value. In addition to tax from currently owned provinces on the campaign map, each side has some additional income which may be from off map provinces, foreign subsidies or other sources of income.~~Surviving troops are paid at the end of the year at half the cost of raising an equivalent new unit.~~If you now have money in your treasury you can raise additional forces.~~Armies cannot be moved in the turn they are raised. No armies can move in the Early Spring turn.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL13, "Hostile forces in a province will cause economic damage due to foraging raids and deliberate devastation. The larger the hostile forces, the greater the damage. This affects the province's future capacity to pay tax and supply armies.~~Economic damage will recover somewhat between campaigning seasons, so the province will eventually recover its original economic and supply value if given sufficent respite from conflict.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL14, "There are six campaigning turns each year: Early Spring, Late Spring, Early Summer, Late Summer, Early Autumn, Late Autumn.~~When you end your turn the enemy will make their moves, if any.~~At the end of the campaigning season, all armies retreat to winter quarters, taxation will be collected and troops paid.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL15, "You can refit an army (bring the units up to strength) if it is in one of your provinces, you have enough money in the treasury, and there is sufficient manpower for the refit available in the province they are in. Refitting an army uses 5 Action Points (AP).~~However, all armies are automatically refitted at the end of each campaign year, the manpower and cost being deducted from throughout your territory automatically. Replacing losses dilutes any experience and elan gains that a unit may have.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL16, "Provinces can be Agricultural, Hilly, Wooded or Mountainous. This affects the sort of battlefield terrain you can expect when a battle occurs in the province, also army movement and tax value.~~The Action Points (AP) required to move an army from one province to an adjacent one depends on the terrain in the destination province: Agricultural 2, Hilly or Wooded 3, Mountains 6.~~Armies can keep moving until they run out of AP.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL18, "This army does not have enough AP left to make that move.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL19, "You can only move armies into adjacent provinces. They will be able to move again after that if they have sufficient AP.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL2, "You can divide your forces in this province if you wish.~~Use the Split Army button to do so. This will open the Split Army screen which will allow you detach some of the units to form a new army.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL21, "At the end of each year taxes are collected and troops paid. Captured provinces only yield half of their normal taxable value. In addition to tax from currently owned provinces on the campaign map, each side has some additional income which may be from off map provinces, foreign subsidies or other sources of income.~~Surviving troops are paid at the end of the year at half the cost of raising an equivalent new unit.~~If you now have money in your treasury you can raise additional forces. Select one of your provinces and then use the Raise New Army button to open the Force Selection screen. The number of units available is restricted by the manpower available in the province and your available funds. Repeat this for other provinces until you have raised all the forces you want or can afford.~~Armies cannot be moved in the turn they are raised. No armies can move in the Early Spring turn.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL22, "You can move any of your armies by dragging its flag icon into an adjacent province, provided that it has enough Action Points (AP) left to enter that province. It takes 2 AP to move into an Agricultural province, 3 AP to move into a Hilly or Wooded province, 6 AP to move into a Mountainous province. An army can make a second or third move if it has sufficient AP.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL3, "You can combine all your forces in this province into one army if you wish.~~Use the Combine Armies button to do so. This action will use up 1 Action Point (AP).",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL4, "~Right click to see details.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL5, "~Drag to an adjacent province to move.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL6, "When an army invades a province and any enemy field army present has been driven off, the army then besieges the town(s) and other strongpoints in the province. The province does not change ownership until these fall.~~While engaged in siege operations an army will usually suffer attrition (loss of men and elan) from combat casualties, desertion and disease.~~At the end of each turn there is a chance that the besieged province will capitulate. This depends on the size of the besieging force and its proportion of infantry and, especially, medium or heavy artillery. It also depends on the duration of continuous siege.~~If the province capitulates, units from the besieging army are assigned to garrison duties. They are removed from the field army roster.~~If the province has not capitulated by the end of autumn, the siege is lifted and the besieging army retreats to winter quarters.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL7, "If the commander of the field forces in a province feels that his army is not strong enough to face an approaching enemy army in battle, he will retreat.~~Retreat is always fraught with risk and the army may suffer attrition (loss of men and elan) from rearguard actions and desertions.", 
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL8, "(If there are sufficient local garrison or militia units in a province to tip the balance in favour of a decision to engage the enemy in battle, these will join their friendly field army for the duration of the battle.~~This can occur when a province with a friendly field army present is invaded, or when a friendly field army moves to the relief of a besieged province.)",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL9, "The size of the army flag icon gives a very rough indication of the relative size of the army.~~When you mouse over an enemy army you will see an estimate of its strength. It is important to remember that this is only an estimate - the army's true strength may be somewhat higher or lower. Your decisions are therefore based on incomplete information, as are those of the enemy.",
IDS_CAMP_TUTORIAL_RESET, "Show previously shown helper messages once more",
IDS_CAMP_VICTORIES, "Victories",
IDS_CAMP_VICTORY, "You are victorious",
IDS_CAMP_VICTORY2, "However, we have little doubt that they will attack again when the treaty expires (or even sooner). We must be ready",
IDS_CAMP_VICTORY_IMMINENT, "victory imminent", // usage: French victory imminent.
IDS_ELAN_ABOVE_AVERAGE, "Enthusiastic",
IDS_ELAN_AVERAGE, "Steady",
IDS_ELAN_ELITE, "Indomitable",
IDS_ELAN_HIGHLY_SUPERIOR, "Fearless",
IDS_ELAN_NERVOUS, "Nervous",
IDS_ELAN_SUPERIOR, "Confident",
IDS_ELAN_TERRIFIED, "Terrified",
IDS_EXPERIENCE, "Experience", // usage: Experience 50% of standard for unit type
IDS_EXPERIENCE_ABBREVIATED, "Exp", // usage: Exp 50%
IDS_EXP_ABOVE_AVERAGE, "Battle-Tested",
IDS_EXP_AVERAGE, "Trained",
IDS_EXP_HIGHLY_SUPERIOR, "Veteran",
IDS_EXP_SUPERIOR, "Battle-Hardened",
IDS_FROM, "from", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army retreated from Quakenwald to Weisskloster
IDS_FULL_ESTABLISHMENT, "of full establishment", // usage: Average unit strength 95% of full establishment
IDS_NEAR, "near", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army lost the battle near Dornfeld
IDS_STANDARD, "of standard for unit type", // usage: Average experience 95% of standard for unit type
IDS_STRENGTH, "Strength", // usage: Strength 50% of full establishment
IDS_STRENGTH_ABBREVIATED, "Str", // usage Str 50%
IDS_THE, "The", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army lost the battle near Dornfeld
IDS_TO, "to", // usage: The Transylvanian 1st army moved from Quakenwald to Weisskloster
IDS_TT_CONFIRM_SPLIT, "Confirm split",
IDS_TT_EXIT_BATTLE, "Retreat from battle",
IDS_EXP_BELOW_AVERAGE, "Partly Trained",

IDS_AUTORESOLVE_BATTLE, "Auto-Resolve Battle",
IDS_CHANCE_OF_VICTORY, "Chance of Victory", // Usage: Chance of victory 45%
IDS_INCLUDING, "Including", // Usage: Including 15% for previous battle record
IDS_PREVIOUS_RECORD, "for previous record", // Usage: Including 15% for previous battle record
IDS_CAMP_AUTORESOLVE_CONFIRM, "Are you sure you want to autoresolve this battle?",